ATHM Textile Industry Stereographs 6524/006 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series III: Pacific Mills Images Organized by Textile Related Subject
  - Engraving and Printing (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 36: Printing machine, side view (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 37: Printing machine, front view (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 38: Line of calico printing machines, overhead view (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 39: Top view of calico printing process (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 40: Printing, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 41: Printing, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 42: Printing, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 43: Calendering (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 44: Calendering or "ironing" (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 45: Copper printing rolls (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 46: Transferring design to copper roller (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Item 47: Copper rolls, close-up (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Napping (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Item 1: Napping (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Item 2: Napping, close-p (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Item 3: Napping (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Item 4: Napping (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Singeing (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 1: Singeing cloth by gas flames (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 2: Singeing cloth by gas flames (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 3: Sewing ends of cloth pieces together before singeing (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 4: Sewing ends of cloth pieces together before singeing (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 5: Sewing ends of cloth pieces together before singeing (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 6: Shearing cloth (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 7: Singeing cloth by gas flames (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 8: Singeing cloth (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 9: Sewing gray cloth pieces together (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 10: Sewing ends of gray cloth pieces before singeing (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Item 11: Singeing (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Tentering (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 1: Tenter, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 1: Delivery end of tenter (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 2: Tenter, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 3: Tenter, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 4: Cloth being fed into starch end tenter (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 5: Cloth being starched in tenter (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 7: Operating starch end of tenter (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 8: Delivery end of tenter (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 9: Tenter, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 10: Tenter, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 11: Starch end of tenter (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 12: Tenter, delivery end (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Item 13: Cloth being stretched in tenter (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Folding and Pressing (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Item 1: Folding finished cloth into pieces of about 40 yards (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Item 2: Folding finished cloth (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Item 3: Folding finished cloth (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Item 4: Pressing and winding finished dress goods onto boards (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Inspecting and Packaging (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 1: Inspecting gray cloth in rolls (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 2: Inspecting gray cloth for imperfections (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 3: Inspecting gray cloth in rolls (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 4: Inspecting gray cloth in rolls (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 5: Inspecting gray cloth for imperfections (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 6: Inspecting cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 7: Packaged bolts of finished cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 8: Finished, folded cloth in bolts (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 9: Folded cloth in bolts (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 10: Stacking folded, banded cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 11: Stacking folded, banded cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 12: Stacking folded, banded cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 13: Examining printed cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 14: Putting paper bands and tickets on finished cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 15: Packaged bolts of finished cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 16: Putting paper bands and tickets on finished cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Item 17: Examining printed cloth (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Wool, Raw Material (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 1: Fleece-from our sheep (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 2: Wool fiber (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 3: Wool fiber (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 4: Fleece-frome our sheep (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 5: One fleece spread over a bale (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 6: A fleece from one sheep (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 7: Covering or fleece of one sheep (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 8: Fleece being examined by the overseer (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 9: Fleece-from our sheep (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 10: Fleece-from our sheep (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 11: A fleece from one sheep (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 12: One fleece spread out on the floor (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 13: View in wool storehouse (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 14: Wool storehouse (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 15: Wool fiber (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 16: Wool fiber (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Item 17: Wool fiber (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Carding, General (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Item 1: General view in card room (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Item 2: View in card room (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Item 3: General view in card room (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Item 4: General view in card room (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Wool Before Carding (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 1: Wool sorter working at his bench (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 2: Wool sorter (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Gelatin silver print, ca. 1918. Black-and-white image depicts a man in work clothes sorting wool in the Pacific Mills. He is surrounded by piles of raw wool; another man in the right background is seated, holding some sort of implement, with a pile of wool in his lap. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 3: Wool goes to carding machine (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 4: Receiving end of wool scouring machine (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 5: Wool sorting (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 6: Truck load of scoured wool (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 7: Clean wool from scouring (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 8: Feeding sorted wool into wool washer (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 9: All wool (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 10: Scouring tanks & automatic rakes (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 11: Scouring tanks & automatic rakes (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 12: Sorting wool for quality & length of fibre (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 13: Wool sorter working at his bench (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 14: Side view of machine from receiving end (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 15: Wool washer showing rakes for moving wool (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 16: All wool (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Item 17: Wool goes to carding machine (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Carding By Flats (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Item 1: Cotton card (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Carding By Rollers (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 1: Delivery end of carding machine (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 2: Wool goes to carding machine (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 3: Detail of carding machine (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 4: Wool goes to carding machine (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 5: Wool goes to carding machine (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 6: Receiving end of carding machine (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 7: View showing wool advancing into card (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 8: Detail of carding machine (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Item 9: Detail of carding machine (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Combing (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Item 1: Combing machine (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Item 2: Combed wool (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Item 3: Truck load of tops (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Item 4: Combing machine (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Item 5: Wool comber (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Yarn Testing (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Item 1: Wool testing for strength of yarn (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Item 2: Wool testing for strength of yarn (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Item 3: Wool testing for strength of yarn (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Worsted Spinning (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Item 1: Worsted spinning (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Woolen mill, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
  - Drawing (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 1: Truck load of gill balls (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 2: English drawing no. 3 (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 3: French drawing-front view (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 4: French drawing-front view (labor-female) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 5: Exhibit - English drawing system (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 6: Exhibit- French drawing system (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 7: First process of French drawing-receiving end (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 8: First process of French drawing - delivery end (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 9: French drawing (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Side view.
    - Item 10: View of gilling machine (Box 14, Folder 9)
      Intersecting gilling
    - Item 11: Compressing gilled slivers into ball form (Box 14, Folder 9)
      "Punch box."
    - Item 12: General view in gill room (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 13: French system drawing frame (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 14: French drawing (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 15: French drawing-front view (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 16: Drawing machines (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 17: English drawing machine no. 1 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 18: Exhibit of top and sliver (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 19: French drawing-front view (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 20: French drawing-front view (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 21: French drawing-front view (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 22: Exhibit of top and sliver (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 23: Wool drawing-first process (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 24: French drawing-top to yarn (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 25: Exhibit-English drawing system (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 26: Exhibit-English drawing system (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 27: Exhibit-English drawing system (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 28: Gill machine no. 2 (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 29: Four spindle drawing frame (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 30: English drawing no. 3 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 31: English drawing machine no. 1 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 32: Two spindle drawing frame (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Item 33: Drawing machines (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Roving (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Item 1: Worsted roving frame (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Item 2: Worsted roving frames (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Item 3: Worsted roving frames (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Item 4: Worsted roving frame (labor - female) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Item 5: [worsted roving frame] (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Item 6: Top-roving yarn (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Item 7: Worsted roving frames (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Spinning, General (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Item 1: "Doffing" boy (labor - child) (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Item 2: "Doffing" boy (labor - child) (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Worsted
  - Mule Spinning (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Item 1: Mule spinning (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Item 2: Mule spinning room (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Item 3: Mule spinning (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Item 4: Worsted 'mule' spinner (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Item 5: Worsted "mule" spinner (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Item 6: Worsted "mule" spinner (labor - male) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Cap Spinning (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Item 1: Worsted cap spinning frames (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Item 2: Doffing (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Item 3: Worsted cap spinning frames (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Item 4: Doffing (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Item 5: Cap spinning (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Twisting (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Item 1: Twisting (female - labor) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Item 2: Twisting (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Item 3: Exhibit: cheese to warping spool (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Item 4: Exhibit-cheese to warping spool (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Item 5: Twisting (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Fiber Testing (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Item 1: Testing yarn (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Item 2: Pacific Mills interior -Inspecting yarn (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Spooling (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Item 1: Exhibit - "top" to "warping spool" (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Item 2: Exhibit "top" to "warping spool" (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Item 3: Exhibit - "top" to warping spool (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Item 4: Exhibit - "top" to warping spool (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Warping and Drawing (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 1: Warping (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 2: Warping room (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 3: Drawing-in (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 4: Web drawing the harness (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 5: Drawing-in (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 6: Web drawing the harness (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 7: Web drawing the reed (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 8: Warping room (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 9: Warping room (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 10: Warping room (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 11: Threads being drawn into reed (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 12: Webb drawing the harness (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 13: Warp tying machine (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 14: [threads being drawn into reed] (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 15: Drawing-in (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 16: Web drawing the harness [close up] (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 17: Warping room (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 18: Warping room (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 19: Warper beams of inspected yarn (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Item 20: Warping room (labor - male & female) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Power Loom Weaving (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Item 1: Broad worsted loom (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Item 2: Weave room (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Weaving Accessories (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Item 1: Worsted filling yarn on bobbin and in loom shuttle (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Item 2: Shuttle and loom harness (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Item 3: Worsted filling yarn on bobbin & in loom shuttle (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Item 4: Shuttle and loom harness (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Item 5: Shuttle in the loom (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Item 6: Shuttle & loom harness (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Dyeing (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 1: Dye mixing (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 2: Dyeing machine (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 3: Drying dyed cloth (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 4: Weighing dyestuffs and drugs (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 5: Taking dyed cloth from "kettle" (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 6: Dyeing machine (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 7: Wetting out and scouring before dyeing (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 8: Dolly [scouring] (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 9: Taking dyed cloth from "kettle" (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 10: Taking dyed cloth from "kettle" (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Item 11: Dolly [scouring] (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Finishing (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Item 1: Conditioning machine (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Item 2: A piece of worsted dress (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Item 3: A piece of worsted dress (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Item 4: A piece of worsted dress (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Winding (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Item 1: Doubling and winding (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Item 2: Winding machine showing hand knotter (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Item 3: Winding machine no. 1 (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Item 4: Winding machine (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Item 5: Pressing 7 winding finished dress goods (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Item 6: Doubling machine (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Inspecting and Packaging (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 1: Packing room (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 2: Banding & ticketing pieces of dress goods (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 3: Banding & ticketing pieces of dress goods (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 4: Packing room (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 5: Gray cloth inspecting room (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 6: Shipping room (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 7: Inspecting cloth (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 8: Inspecting room (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 9: cloth examination (final) (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 10: Shipping room (labor - male) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 11: Cloth inspection room (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 12: Cloth inspection room (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Item 13: Cloth examination - no. 1 (labor - female) (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Stereoscopic Viewer (Box 16, Folder 1)